# **Shannon Owings**

2709 Scott Avenue Fort Worth, Texas, 76103 817-933-4565 shannon.owings21@gmail.com

#### **ABOUT**

I will be graduating with a B.S.A degree in Biology from the University of Texas at Austin in May 2020. I will then be going to medical school with the hope of becoming a trauma surgeon. I have experience as an Undergraduate Teaching Assistant, Optometric Technician, caterer, bartender, babysitter, and lifeguard. I have also served as President of one of the largest organizations at UT. I believe that I possess great communication, leadership, and customer service skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

Calvary Christian Academy, Valedictorian of 2016

University of Texas at Austin, The College of Natural Sciences, Austin, TX

Bachelor of Science and Arts, Biology, Minor in Spanish

Study Abroad Program-University of Sevilla, Spain, Summer 2018

G.P.A.: 3.9094

First Generation College Student

Anticipated Graduation Date: May 23, 2020

## **ACTIVITIES AND LEADERSHIP**

- -President of Global Medical Training, 2019-2020
- -Volunteer Program Co-Chair for Dell Children's Medical Center, 2019-2020
- -Volunteer Coordinator for Global Medical Training, 2018-2019
- -Research Assistant in Music and Memory Lab, 2019
- -Associate Delegation Leader for Fort Worth Sister Cities, 2018
- -Global Medical Training Mission Trip to Dominican Republic, 2018
- -Global Medical Training Mission Trip to Peru, 2019
- -Member of Alpha Epsilon Delta, 2018-2019
- -Member of Alpha Chi Omega, 2017-2019
- -Freshman Research Initiative-Genome Engineering, 2017
- -Member of Texas Triathlon, 2017
- -Member of Global Medical Training, 2017-present
- -Member of College Young Life, 2016-present

## COMMUNITY SERVICE

-Dell Children's Medical Center, 2018-present

I have volunteered at the information desk as well as the PANDA/PACU area. Working at the information desk entailed answering questions, walking families to several departments, delivering flowers and gifts to patients, and more. Volunteering in the PANDA/PACU area involves stocking rooms, transporting patients, attending to basic needs in postop, and more.

-We Are Blood, 2018

I volunteered as a Canteen Host and monitored reactions in the donors after they gave blood.

-Fort Worth Sister Cities, 2014-2018

This volunteer program raises funds to help pay for international exchanges for their students.

-Care Communities, 2017

I visited a cancer patient once a week and help with any chores they might need around the house.

-Cook Children's, 2015-2017

I volunteered in the PACU Recovery. My primary responsibilities included patient walk-downs, cleaning, and attending to patients' needs.

-Fortress Youth Development Center 2014-2016

I helped children with their homework, engage in outdoor activities, and sometimes serve the kids snacks.

-Meals on Wheels 2013-2016

I help deliver meals to a group of elderly people.

-Christmas Wish Program for Foster Children, 2012-present

I collect gifts for the children and sort the toys and books.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

- -Undergraduate Teaching Assistant for Fundamentals of Biochemistry (BCH 369), 2019-2020
- -Undergraduate Teaching Assistant for Introductory Biology I (BIO 311C), Fall 2017
- -Eyeworks, 2017
  - Optometric technician at Eyeworks/Chu Eye Institute
- -Teresa's Event Staffing, 2013-present
  - On-call caterer in several cities in Texas
- -Babysitting, 2013-present
- -Lifeguarding—2015-2018

## **AWARDS**

- -College Scholar, 2018-2020
- -University Honors, 2016-2019
- -Nominee for 2017-2018 BIO Outstanding TA/UGTA Award
- -Willya L. Cantrell scholarship recipient, 2018
- -Texas Exes Scholarship recipient, 2016
- -Highest Ranking Graduate scholarship recipient, 2016
- -AP Scholar, 2015
- -Fort Worth Sister Cities Harashin Scholar, 2014

## SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Skills- Customer service, leadership, interpersonal skills Interests- Traveling, sports, concerts, yoga, writing